Edgar Filipe da Silva Domingues

Software Engineer

I'm a software engineer with a passion for solving real world problems and **over 10 years** of experience. By putting my best in everything I do, and having "kaizen" in my mind, I continuously improve my work and the work of my team, following agile and software development good practices to increase business value and user satisfaction. I have **Experience** working with teams of different cultures and languages, both onsite and remote, and developing software for different areas, including robotics, telecommunications, call centers, e-commerce, fintech, and banking. On my **free time** I'm either working on side projects or outside enjoying nature by doing sport. I also help in organizing orienteering events.

Experience

Bru Textiles - Senior Software Engineer

2021-12 - present

- Develop software for 12 warehouses, a 3D rendering engine, and internal tools.
- Java, Spring Boot, Event Sourcing with Axon Framework and Axon Server, Python, JavaScript, React, AWS, Kubernetes.

Talkdesk - Software Engineer

2020-08 - 2021-12

- Develop back-end software for Call Center Workforce Management.
- Microservices architecture with Java, MicroProfile, and Quarkus.
- Provide mentoring to junior developers.

Isobar Switzerland, Leiria – *Software Engineer / Senior Consultant* 2016-12 – 2020-08

- Developed Client Onboarding solutions for banks using Java Spring BPM engines.
- Full stack developer in B2B e-shop using jQuery and SAP Hybris.
- Worked remotely with distributed teams around the world.

La Redoute, Leiria – *Software Engineer*

2014-09 - 2016-12

- Development of the back-end to handle the life cycle of orders from request until shipping.
- Created Java Spring Batch applications to process large quantities of data in an efficient way.
- Migrated COBOL programs to Java Spring and integrated them with legacy systems.

Portugal Telecom Inovação, Aveiro - Software Engineer

2011-09 - 2014-09

- Developed software for research projects and products, in the areas of context-awareness, social networks, connection management, VoIP, etc.
- Created application for Windows, Android and iPhone (Java, C/C++, C# and Objective-C)

Education

University of Aveiro – M.Sc. in Computers and Telematics Engineering 2009-2011

Dissertation: "Development of Behaviors for Humanoid Robot"

Publications: "Humanoid Behaviors: from Simulation to a Real Robot", EPIA 2011, Springer

University of Aveiro – Degree in Computers and Telematics Engineering 2006 - 2009

Certifications and Training

- Java Upgrade (11 to 17 and beyond) Info Support (2023-06)
- Certified Scrum Master (CSM) Scrum Alliance (2017-05)
- French Classes Linécole (2016-07)
- Test-Driven Development Practices in Java pluralsight.com (2016-05)
- Training in Trail Orienteering Course Setting and Planning Portuguese Orienteering Federation (2015-12)
- Training in Technology Project Management PT Inovação (2013-10)
- Advanced training in SIP PT Inovação (2013-06)
- Training "jRuby on Rails" PT Inovação (2012-07)

Personal Info

Web

edgardomingues.com

E-mail

edgar.domingues@gmail.com

Technical Skills

Java, JEE, Spring, MicroProfile, Quarkus, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Git, BPM, Appway, COBOL, DB2, AS400, SOAP, REST, Maven, JUnit, Mockito, C/C++, C#, Android SDK and NDK, iOS, Objective-C, Kotlin, Python, Flutter, Dart, Solidity, Gherkin, Cucumber, Scrum, TDD, BDD, Axon Framework, Axon Server, Docker, Kubernetes. RabbitMQ, Kafka, etc.

Awards

- WealthBriefing Swiss Awards 2020
- Highest grade finalist in the engineering courses of 2011.
- Merit scholarship in 2007/2008 and 2010/2011.
- Honor student on high school.
- 3º place in the Microsoft Webmaster 2006.

Interests

- Orienteering
- Traveling
- Automation